GEORGE MCMURRAY

(650) 880-7464 | gmcmurray1493@gmail.com

Director of Operations: New Product Process Owner, Sustaining/Manufacturing Engineering and Product Quality. Expert in new product introduction (NPI) of Power Integrated Circuits and modules for cell phone, computing and cloud server applications. Designed business processes for new product funnel control, development resource management, design methodology. Direct customer experience on Quality and Reliability issues. Product Life Cycle management from idea to end of life management.

Areas of expertise:

Quality Systems | Production Statistical Quality Control | IC Reliability Testing | Design of Experiments | Design Process Methodology | Process Optimization and Management | Program/Project Management | Yield Management | Customer Returns | Failure Analysis Techniques | Root Cause Analysis | Design for Test Manufacturing | Risk Assessment and FMEA|Problem Solving Techniques

EXPERIENCE

ON SEMICONDUCTOR, Sunnyvale, CA

Director of Mobile Operations

11/2018 - 04/2021

Expanded role which included production sustaining engineering group of 30 engineers. Worked with internal factories and outside foundries to achieve consistent cost reduction, drive manufacturing capacity expansion, and drove outgoing quality improvements. Created new metrics to track and improve Business Processes in Quality performance and New Product Development organizational efficiency.

- Achieved cost improvement of over \$2M per year by improving production yield, reducing test time and optimizing Bill of Materials. Resolved test capacity issues impacting supply chain through test time reduction and test program conversion to different platforms and test time reductions to meet customer demand.
- Lowered parts per million (PPM) defect rates at customer factories through improving outgoing test screening and assisting debugging of customer applications. Worked directly with customers, subcons, foundries and internal factories to resolve quality excursions.
- Total Product Life Management: From product idea, product launch, production and customer product change notification process.

Director of Program Management

01/2016-10/2018

Led team of program managers to manage New Product Introduction (NPI) projects in Mobile Division. Devised and enhanced a 5-phase NPI development methodology flow to achieve consistently high-quality product releases. Formed and managed division steering committee to review and improve NPI execution performance. Mapped business and manufacturing processes to improve organizational execution in New Product introductions. Integrated and developed

GEORGE MCMURRAY

Best Practices from multiple business units into the Division. Conducted monthly data analysis of key design engineering resource usage. Reported to senior management monthly, data-driven KPI metrics in new product introductions, innovation, quality

- Led team of 10 program managers working on over 50 active NPI projects at any given time. Drove successful project performance in on-time production releases and first samples delivered to customers.
- Improved throughput and cycle time of key products targeted at mobile phone projects. Established and drove continuous improvement of NPI process across multiple business units in the Mobile Division.
- Streamlined checklist and IC design methodology with the adoption of JAMA as a tool to enhance and accelerate product definition, verification and validation of products in development.
- Successfully managed external audits for ISO9001 and IATF16949 certifications.

FAIRCHILD SEMICONDUCTOR, San Jose, CA

Worldwide Director of NPI Quality and Failure Analysis and Reliability

12/2012-1/2016

Worldwide responsibility for entire failure analysis, reliability labs and NPI quality. Led over 100 engineers, technicians, and operators responsible for multi-chip modules, integrated circuits and discrete FETs. Drove quality improvement initiatives targeting technical process improvements.

- Managed 7 failure analysis (FA) labs in Malaysia, Korea, Philippines, Taiwan and United States. Successfully consolidated them down to 5 labs while improving capability and cycle time while maintaining throughput. Improved service performance at factory FA labs with the additions of modern SEMs and precision decapsulation tools. Retained and redistributed key EFA engineers from consolidated labs.
- Managed 8 reliability labs in Malaysia, Korea, Philippines, Taiwan and United States.
 Successfully consolidated down to 5 labs while improving capability and cycle time and maintaining through put. Modernized burn-in oven capability to include real-time monitoring capability.
- Resolved major sole source product quality issue preventing lines down issue which was worth \$30M p.a. in revenue by using problem solving techniques using extensive data analysis, determining root cause through Design of Experiments

NATIONAL SEMICONDUCTOR, Sunnyvale, CA

Sunnyvale Mobile Site Manager

1/2008-4/2012

Led analog/digital design and applications team of over 25 engineers. Product responsibility included mobile PMICs, stand-alone DC/DC converters and LDOs.

- Defined architecture for Pico Projector chip set for smart phone application.
- Designed PMIC+MEMs driver for novel MEMs mirror to implement laser-based video projection for a Pico Projector used in a smart phone. First-pass success achieved in only 13 months from product definition to clean design.

GEORGE MCMURRAY

EDUCATION

- PhD candidate (ABD) Operations Research and Industrial Engineering, University of California at Berkeley
- MS Systems Engineering, University of Arizona, Tucson AZ
- MSEE Electrical Engineering, Southern Methodist University, Dallas TX
- BSEE Dual Bachelors, Mathematics and Electrical Engineering, Duke University, Durham NC